clrwtr.com 2019-03-10

# Privacy Policy | Valin

## Valin® Privacy Statement

Valin Corporation and our affiliates/brands [Heat Trace Specialists, The Valve Shop and Cardinal] (“we,” “us,” and “Valin”) value your trust and are committed to handling your personal information in a safe and responsible manner.  This Privacy Statement applies to information you provide and that we collect through our website(s), [[www.valin.com](https://www.valin.com/), [www.valinonline.com](https://www.valinonline.com/), [www.custodytransferlact.com](http://www.custodytransferlact.com/),[ www.heattracespecialists.com](http://%20www.heattracespecialists.com/), [www.thevalveshop.com](http://www.thevalveshop.com/)] and any additional websites, microsites, mobile sites or applications that Valin may own or operate (collectively, the “Sites”).  This Privacy Statement does not cover any information collected offline or outside of the Sites by Valin, unless specifically stated otherwise below.  This Privacy Statement describes:

  * What kinds of information we collect about you;
  * Why we collect this information about you;
  * How we use this information;
  * When and to whom we share this information;
  * How we protect this information; and
  * Your ability to make choices about how we collect, use, and share your information.

### **What information does Valin collect about me and why?**

Valin collects your personal and other information that you provide to us when you register or create an online credit card or credit line account with us.  The personal information you provide to us may include a user ID and password that you create, your first and last name, your job title, your company name, your industry, your email address, your phone number, your fax number, your billing address information and your shipping address information.  If you create an online credit card account with us, you will also provide your credit card number, expiration date and CVV code.  Companies requesting a credit line account may also provide us name(s) of parent or other affiliated companies, number of years in business, number of years at a current address, number of employees, a description of the type of business, a U.S. federal ID number, a Dun & Bradstreet number, and the name and phone number of person(s) to contact for accounting purposes.  When you register or create an online account with us, we will assign you a Customer ID number.

Element Payment Services, Inc., a Vantiv Company (NYSE: VNTV) (“Element”) is the payment card processing company that handles the financial transactions of Valin’s e-commerce website, [www.valinonline.com](https://www.valinonline.com/).  Element uses its PCI DSS compliant technology to securely process, transmit and store payment card related data.  Elements’ privacy policy can be found [here](https://www.vantiv.com/privacy-policy).  Valin does not collect or store your credit card information.

Information about your computer or device, including domain type, browser version, IP address and geo-location data may also be collected by us or by one of our service providers to learn about your use of our Sites.  Valin also gathers information about where you and other visitors go on our Sites to see which areas are of most interest and to tailor our communications to your respective interests.  This helps us improve our Sites for all visitors and customers, and your browsing experience with us. 

### **How does Valin use my information?**

We use the information we collect from you for the following purposes:

  * To set up an online account, an online credit card account or an online credit line account for you to facilitate your access to and navigation of our Sites, so that you can make purchases online, to process your orders and to respond to any questions about your order;
  * To communicate with you via email, mail, and by other methods of communications about Valin’s services, products and other Valin business matters;
  * To improve our services to you and improve the quality of your experience with our Sites;
  * To provide advertisements to you on our Sites and other websites about Valin products and services based on your browsing and shopping preferences;
  * To analyze and determine trends and statistics

The businesses of Valin and its Sites are not designed for children.  Valin does not knowingly collect any personal information from or about a child under the age of 13 years. 

Valin uses cookies to help improve our Sites and visitor and customer experience.  A cookie is a piece of data that a website sends to a visitor’s computer’s hard drive for record-keeping purposes.  A cookie assigns a unique identification to your computer or mobile device, and is then used by a website to recognize your browser as a previous visitor so that your browsing experience can be personalized.  Such a website saves and remembers any preferences or other actions you took while visiting the website. For example, if you place items in your shopping cart at [www.valinonline.com](https://www.valinonline.com/), we may use cookies to keep those items in your cart for your future access. We may also use cookies to recognize you when you return to our Sites to understand your use of our Sites so we can improve the features of our Sites and tailor communications relevant to you.

We may also use our own cookies to provide you with personalized online display advertising tailored to your interests.  Our cookies do not contain your name, address or any financial information.  Nonetheless, to opt out of Valin cookies used for this online advertising, [click here](mailto:marketing@valin.com?subject=Please%20remove%20me%20from%20your%20distribution%20list).

You can refuse cookies by turning them off in your Internet or mobile browser. In order to disable cookies, please consult your browser's help section for instructions. If you turn off cookies, however, you may not be able to use some or any of the features of our Sites.

We may use "pixel tags" (sometimes called web beacons, web bugs or clear gifs), which are transparent tiny graphic images that are placed in the code on our Sites and possibly in our emails and collect information about website usage, email response and tracking. Pixel tags help us analyze our customers' online behavior and measure the effectiveness of our Sites and advertising.

Google Analytics.  Valin uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses "cookies", which are text files placed on your computer to help analyze how users use the Sites. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the Sites, including your IP address, will be transmitted to and stored by Google on its servers. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the Sites, compiling reports on activity for operators of the Sites and providing other services relating to activity on the Sites and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. To read Google Analytics security and privacy principles, please [click here](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en).

Advertising.  We work with service providers such as AdRoll that help us track, collect and analyze this information. AdRoll uses algorithms to select which websites to serve our advertisements to you based on where you would prefer to see our ads on the web. We ask AdRoll to deliver only those ads that are relevant to you based on where you browse online.  You can read AdRoll’s privacy policy [here](https://www.adroll.com/about/privacy). You can opt-out of receiving targeted ads served by us or other advertising companies: AdRoll is also a member of the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) and adheres to the NAI Code of Conduct. You may use the NAI opt out tool [here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/), which will allow you to opt out of seeing targeted ads from us and from other NAI approved member companies.

We use pixel tags, either alone or in conjunction with cookies, to collect information about your visit, including the pages you view, the features you use, the links you click, and other actions you take in connection with the Sites. This information may include your mobile device or computer's IP address, your browser type, your operating system, date and time information, and other technical information about your computer or mobile device. We may also track certain information about the identity of the website you visited immediately before coming to our Sites as well as the identity of the websites you visit after you leave our Sites.

We may also use Local Shared Objects (sometimes called "flash cookies"), browser web storage (including HTML5) and application data caches. These are used to enhance your user experience, for example, by storing your user preferences and settings. These mechanisms operate similarly to browser cookies, but can store data more complex than simple text. To find out more about flash cookies or how to disable them, please [click here](https://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-local-shared-objects-flash.html).

### **How does Valin Respond to “Do Not Track” Signals?**

Some web browsers may transmit "do not track" signals to the websites and other online services with which the browser communicates. There is no standard that governs what websites can or should do when they receive these signals. We currently do not take action in response to these signals. By visiting our Sites, you consent to our placement of cookies, pixel tags, Local Shared Objects and other similar technologies on your computer and/or mobile device.

### **Will my information be shared?**

We do not disclose personally identifiable information about you to third parties for their independent use unless: (1) you request or authorize us to do so; (2) we are required to do so in order to comply with the law (for example, to comply with a search warrant, subpoena or court order); (3) we are required to enforce an agreement we have with you; (4) we are required to do so in order to protect our rights, property or safety, or the rights, property or safety of our employees or others; (5) we are required to in order to address emergencies or acts of God; or (6) as necessary to address disputes or claims, including to persons holding a legal or beneficial interest in, for example, a Valin account.

Valin shares information about our customers with service providers such as Elements and AdRoll as described in this Privacy Statement, so that we can provide better service to you, such as collecting, storing and managing customer information; providing customer services; taking and fulfilling orders; processing credit card information; conducting promotions and surveys for our brands; suggesting store locations nearby and communicating effectively with our customers. We restrict those service providers from making any use of your information other than to help us provide better service to you.

We may also allow service providers to collect information about your online activities through cookies and other technologies so that these entities can provide certain services to us. For example, we contract with AdRoll to serve ads on our behalf across the Internet.

### **California Residents Privacy Rights Request for Third Party Information**

Residents of California may request a list of third parties to whom Valin has disclosed their personal information during the preceding year for the direct marketing purposes of those third parties by sending an email to [marketing@valin.com](mailto:marketing@valin.com) or a written letter addressed to:

Valin Corporation  
Attention:  Marketing Manager  
1941 Ringwood Avenue  
San Jose, California 95131

In all such requests, please reference “California Privacy Rights Request for Third Party Information” in your letter and include your full name, street address, city, state and zip code.  Valin will not accept requests via telephone or facsimile or those that do not provide complete information.

### **How will Valin protect my information?**

Valin uses Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology to help keep your online information safe.  SSL technology encrypts your information before it is transmitted to help protect it from being decoded by anyone other than Valin.  Our Sites have also been authenticated by Verisign and we use SSL encryption to transmit confidential information during.

To help protect the privacy of data and personally identifiable information you provide to us through the Sites, Valin maintains physical, technical and administrative safeguards.

We restrict access to your personally identifiable information to those who need to know that information in order for us to provide services to you. In addition, we train our employees about the importance of confidentiality and maintaining the privacy and security of your information. We commit to taking appropriate disciplinary measures to enforce our employees' privacy responsibilities.

We use Element to employ its PCI DSS compliant technology and practices for collecting, processing, storing and otherwise handling all aspects of financial transactions on our e-commerce Sites including [www.valinonline.com](https://www.valinonline.com/).  Again, Valin does not collect or store any of your credit card or financial account information.

Please note that this Privacy Statement only addresses Valin’s use and disclosure of your personally identifiable information. Please be aware that the Sites may contain links to other websites, Valin is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other websites, and Valin is not liable for their conduct with respect to personally identifiable information. When you visit another website, you should carefully read the privacy statement of such website.

While Valin implements SSL technology and other security measures described in this Privacy Statement to protect your information, please note that no data transmitted over the Internet or any other public network is guaranteed to be 100% secure.

### **What choices do I have with regard to my information?**

You can access or change your information in your account profile at any time.  To do so, simply log on at  [www.valinonline.com](https://www.valinonline.com/) click on the "My Account" tab in the upper right hand corner of the main home page. You will then be able to change information stored in your account profile, and then click “Save” when you complete your changes.

You can also change or access this information by contacting our brands. For contact information, [click here](mailto:marketing@valin.com). Please be sure to include or have ready your full name, address, phone number and e-mail address.

### **What if I am accessing Valin’s Sites from outside the United States?**

If you are visiting any of Valin’s Sites from a location outside of the United States, please know that you will be connected to servers located within the United States which may or may not have data protection laws equivalent to the laws of your country of residence.  By providing your information to us through the Sites, you are consenting to the transfer of your personal information to facilities located outside of your country of residence, and understand that your information will be stored and processed in accordance with U.S. law.

### **How do I unsubscribe or opt out of Valin emails?**

You may join our email lists and receive information about our products and services at various points during your visit to any of the Sites. Also, if you provide us with your email address when you register or create an account online, update your account, log in, place an order, make a customer service inquiry, or apply for a credit line, you may automatically be added to our email list and receive marketing or promotional information from us.

You can use the procedures described below to opt out of Valin marketing. Please note that your opt-out request may take up to 30 business days to process, and you may receive communications from us in the meantime. Please note that if you make subsequent purchases from our Sites, we will confirm your order by e-mail, and we may need to contact you by phone, e-mail, or U.S. postal mail with other questions regarding your order.

If you prefer not to receive any marketing or promotional information from Valin, please contact us at (800) 774-5630, [marketing@valin.com](mailto:marketing@valin.com?subject=Please%20remove%20me%20from%20your%20distribution%20list) or by writing to:

Valin Corporation  
Attention: Marketing Manager  
1941 Ringwood Avenue  
San Jose, California 95131

Please be sure to include your full name, email address, telephone number, mailing address and, specifically, what information you do not want to receive. For example:

"I prefer not to receive email marketing."  
"I prefer not to receive direct mail marketing."  
"I prefer not to receive telephone marketing calls."  
"I prefer not to receive mobile marketing messages."

You may also click the unsubscribe link found at the bottom of any Valin marketing emails to be removed from future email marketing.

### **What if there are changes to this Privacy Statement or if I have questions about it?**

We may update our Privacy Statement from time to time. If we make material changes to this Privacy Statement, we will notify you by posting the changes on our Sites. Please check this Privacy Statement from time to time because by visiting our Sites, you agree to accept any changes to our Privacy Statement.

If you have any questions about our Privacy Statement, please contact us by calling (800) 774-5630, or emailing [marketing@valin.com](mailto:marketing@valin.com),, or writing to us at:

Valin Corporation  
Attention: Marketing Manager  
1941 Ringwood Avenue  
San Jose, California 95131

Effective Date:  November 2, 2015

Last modified:  November 11, 2015
